# Max Ortman

Maxrort@gmail.com, 847-346-5909, LinkedIn

#### Skills & Abilities

Fluent in C++, Python, Java, Swift, and other languages. I have experience working as a team member and leading teams. I love to learn new things and I'm always trying to improve. Inquisitive self-starter and quick learner. Programming language enthusiast and proficient in C++ and Python to a high level having experience in still-in-development features like C++26 reflection. I want to be on a team that works with each other closely and enthusiastic and committed to the task at hand. I have worked on multiple video game projects at Digipen where I worked with a group to develop a game. In 2 of the 3 game projects, I was the tech lead. I have also worked on a long-term project, a Discord bot, for betting fake points on Valorant matches. It incorporates Web Scraping, SQLAlchemy for the database, Matplotlib, and many other features.

Portfolio: <a href="https://maxortgit.github.io/">https://maxortgit.github.io/</a>

#### EXPERIENCE

# June 2023 - August 2024 Summers

Instructor, iD Tech Camps

- Taught children and teens 7-17 about different programming concepts
- The first summer I taught both online one-on-one and online week long group lessons
- · The second year taught in person week-long classes
- · Taught Machine Learning, OpenAl API, Unreal Engine, Python, Java, and C++

### June 2021 - August 2023 Summers

Marketing Assistant, Berkshire Hathaway HomeServices Starck Real Estate

- · Assist the Marketing Department with printing marketing materials
- · Correlate and package materials for distribution

### September 2022 -May 2024

Various School Projects

- · Two semester-long projects and one year-long project making video games
- The year-long game project was me as tech lead and 7 others making a game with a custom engine in C++
- Made most of the gameplay features along with many core systems like the editor tool, JSON serializing, performance optimization, and much more
- · Managed the programmers and coordinated with the designers
- · Our project ended with the most amount of "kudos" out of any other project that year
- · Outlined projects more on my portfolio

### EDUCATION AND EXTRA CURRICULUM

August 2022 - present

College, Redmond, WA, Digipen Institute of Technology, 3.9 GPA

Majoring in Computer Science and Machine Learning

Built machine learning models

Learned how to work within a team

August 2018 - April 2022

High School, Arlington Heights, IL, John Hersey High School, 4.0 GPA

Robotics – Work with a group to develop a robot and develop and write code to make the

robot work. There are competitions throughout the year

Esports Club – Coach and IGL of Varsity Valorant team making state

Graduated with High Honors

Won the 2022 Computer Science award

### REFERENCES

Cory Flanagan, Camp Director, iDTech Camps Seattle 352-613-4376

Mark Pullinger, Vice President of Marketing, Berkshire Hathaway Starck Real Estate 847-226-7700

Alex Falkowski, Former Engineering Lab Technician, Pensar Development 425-667-1015